Ben Zelinski

bziggz@gmail.com | Berkshires, MA | www.benzelinski.com

Profile

I'm a Software Engineer based in the Berkshires (MA). I'm the co-creator of Campion, an edge-deployed, circuit-breaking middleware that helps distributed architectures fail gracefully. I'm GCP-ACE certified, an have experience with Cloudflare and AWS. Currently I'm at CipherHealth, where I'm integrating a legacy Rails monolith with Node-based GCP micro-services, while doubling as my team's Agile Delivery Manager.

Skills

Backend — Node, TypeScript, FeathersJS, NestJS, Ruby, Rails, SQL, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, SFTP, RESTful API's | **Frontend** — Javascript (ES6), JQuery, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, ERB, HAML, Vue.js, Bootstrap | **Cloud** — GCP (ACE Certified), Terraform, AWS, Cloudflare, Digital Ocean | **Tools** — Docker, Kubernetes, Postman, OpenAPI/Swagger, Gitlab, Github, Jira, Twilio, Google, Agile

Professional Experience

Software Engineer && Agile Delivery Manager, CipherHealth

2021 – present

- Currently integrating Rails monolith with Node/TS, GCP-Deployed micro-services
- Delivered multiple high-impact, high-value projects
- Consistent, measurable success as ADM across multiple teams
 - Praised by teammates for morale/personnel management
 - Praised by leadership for team output and metrics
- Coordinated world-wide response to live incident as de facto Interim Manager
- Co-authored Feathers-Hook-Breaker, an open-source NPM circuit breaker for FeathersJS
 - Guarantees message rate SLA on two applications at CipherHealth

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, *Campion ⊘*

2020 - 2021

- Co-authored Campion's Case Study: https://campion-breaker.github.io/
- Co-created Campion, an edge-deployed, circuit-breaking middleware that helps distributed architectures fail gracefully
- Designed and built on both Cloudflare and AWS using Node.js and React/Redux, published to NPM
- Operates as a middleware proxy injected into the request/response cycle

Various Management Roles in Hospitality and Wine Industries

2004 - 2019

2000 - 2004

- Co-founded The Bee's Knees Baking Company NYC
- Wine Director and Manager at Mustard's Grill Napa, CA
- Sommelier Del Frisco's Chicago || Harvest Grunt Sonoma, CA

Education

Launch School, https://launchschool.com/employers ⊘ 2019 – 2020 Mastery-based program teaching programming with a strong emphasis on fundamentals.

BFA Dramatic Performance, College-Conservatory of Music at the University of Cincinnati

Awards

Eagle Scout, BSA 365 2000